[Applause]
So, he
said, I repeat this phrase, that if
you reach the third level of the Third
Path,
and it's from the second path, sorry, you don't have to
worry about being reborn in
a lower realm anymore.
If you've been to DC programs
lately, I've told you, you just understand
the pen and you can reach this
third one.
And that's
correct, but there's a little more to it.
Alex, I was asked to explain
some special ideas that happen on the
second
path.
[Music] I'm
going to teach it on
Saturday, and today I'm just going to review
philosophy books with
you and teach you about the second
path and the third
level, straight from the old books. On
Saturday, I'm going to
be friendly for the
users. I didn't have time to go as
deep as I'd like,
using books for these
classes, and I didn't have time to review them
all. We used a special
search program, but even so, I didn't have time to
review them
all. So I'll try to do it for
Saturday,
but here's what we have so far.
So there are three groups of
books. One is called Kangur, which are the
books that Buddha himself spoke about.
that reached Tibet.
How many? 990 or something like 1000
books. And then there are
explanations from India
about those
books.
How many?
3700.
Around
5000 ancient books arrived in
Tibet about 1000
years ago. And the Tibetan explanations of
those 5000
books. There are about
100,000. We've already cataloged
14,141,000 in
Russia. It took us 14 years to make that
catalog. [Music] I'm going to give you different
sources, and I'm going to go back to
the Buddha's discourse.
How about we start with a
story? How do you find this idea that you do
n't have to go to lower rebirths?
[Applause]
In the teachings of Lord
Buddha, I'm
going to read you a
sutra. Let's... Well, let's do...
[Applause] Good
luck.
Third level of this second
path. We have to give it a name. So
the third level of the second path is
called
mastery. Convince into a great
[Applause]
master. And what is the name of the
Bodhisattuna? This is the story of how a Bodhisattuna
reached that...
[Applause]
level and his name, his name is
Ma, our
Buddha is telling the story
[Applause]
to his
students of reaching that level where he
no longer has to
[Applause] go
down. There is a great debate about whether he is
a Buddha or not.
In the
teachings, he
is already a
Buddha. In
everyone's teachings, he is going to be the fourth Buddha in this
world. He is the next Buddha to come
here and he is very
close.
[Applause]
Bu is teaching his students and
tells them, I am going to give you the example of
someone who did work
hard. [
Applause]
Sutra, it is called the Bodhisattva Sutra, who
has a jewel in the topknot of his head
or in the knot, as the
ancient yogis used to style their hair with a knot.
Here speaking, once upon a time,
billions of
years ago, a
certain Buddha came to that world, a
different world, and his
name
means "
bad" in Spanish. It comes from Sanskrit and
means "without
blemish." Yoca means "world," it
also means "
light."
You who know, do you know what "
light" means? That Buddha lived billions
of
years ago. That world was very
peaceful, very
prosperous. The people were happy.
[Music]
The harvests were very
good and the world was full of
gods and
[Music]
humans.
So one day the Buddha of that world, whose name is
Vimala Aluca, the light of the
world, excuse me, immaculate light, a super clean,
super
clear light, had
96,960 million
students. How did he buy them cappuccino?
No, those were the lowest-ranking students,
and
the average lifespan at that time was
84,000. At that time there was a young
king.
His name was...
he was
handsome,
attractive, good complexion,
rich, and he was only 16
years old
because he was a spoiled rich young man. He was very
arrogant. That Buddha lived in his city,
but he never went to hear the Buddha
teach. He
never went to hear the Buddha teach. He never saw him
and didn't
[Music]
respect him. I see a good seed in
this young
king.
If someone teaches him with a lot of
patience, he has
potential. He can have great spiritual achievements.
[Music]
If someone wants to work with him, he
will slowly change his mind and come to my
class and also become a
Buddha.
[Music]
So the Buddha called 84 students to
a
meeting between  You 84,000 wedding
students
[Applause] of
mine. I need one to sit at the foot
of the King's palace gate
until you
gather, are you,
and then convince him to
come to my
class. So I need a
volunteer. And people started raising
their
hands. There he said, "Oh, and I forgot to
tell you, you're going to have to sit at the
foot of his gate for 84,000
years,
and during that time you won't have any
good times, and people will hurt you
for 84 years while
you wait
[Applause]
gate
[Music]. That
means they're going to yell at you, they're not going to
let you stand up, and they're going to call you
bad names for 84,000
[Applause]
years." So if anyone would like to
volunteer,
we're going to hand out a sulim unim. It's a really cool
custom that we still have
in the
monastery. It's the way to take a vow
for 2,000 years. For 2 years in a
monastery, they give everyone a small
stick of that size.
And it's still
used in my monastery. At that time there were
monks, and oh, when we want to take a
vow, we do
n't  They gave them a
stick; there were like two
trays.
If you voted yes, you put it in one, and if you didn't vote, you
put it in the
other. It was crazy because 100 sticks
made a big
pile. We should
use them. Then he handed out all the
sticks
and said, "Whoever wants to volunteer, put your
stick
here." Nobody put it there.
The Lord came by again. "
Please think about
doing it." And they cast their
vote again, and nobody put it there. The
third
time, nobody put it there.
[Music] It
means he loves good karma, loves
working hard, like a
warrior. It means burning, burning energy, like when
the
energy... He got up from his
seat,
put his habit to the side. Whenever you talk
to the Lord, you put it like this. And he
knelt on his right knee,
which is how you're supposed to
talk to the Lord,
and he put his hands on his heart and made
a prostration to the Lord.
[Applause]
I am happy to leave my happiness for
84 years, and I will not be discouraged.
[Music] I
promise.
Whatever abuse people give me, I'll
be
relaxed. I'll be the one sitting at the
foot of the King's door.
When a person does a very good
deed, the whole world trembles. The world
can't sustain such good
karma. So the world holds all
the cities and all the
countries. When a Buddha says something
incredible, the world can't bear the
weight of that great karma, and there's an
earthquake. Six times, six earthquakes
came,
and 8,000 angels sang in the
sky, and the song goes like this:
Oh Lord Buddha, the one who burns the
[Music]
energy, you are putting on the
[Applause]
armor, the energy armor. We talked
about that in Germany.
He spoke very well
in
[Applause]
Sanskrit, in the
Heart Sutra. All the sutras were spoken
by the Buddha. In the Heart Sutra, he only
spoke two words:
[Applause] "
Boo,
good job, good
job." At the King's palace, he
sat and waited at the
door,
and everyone who passed through that door
abused him. They said things to him: "You're a
fool, you're an
idiot," and just for fun, they went down the road
and started on him.  to
throw and then they hit him with
their
hands and other people said no, we shouldn't give him
better
blows,
throw fists of
[Applause]
earth. He saw and heard and he felt
[Music]
but he didn't feel it, he didn't
say anything back, he
never got
angry and he didn't go back to where he used to
live. In fact, his compassion kept
increasing and
increasing,
so he was already years old when he arrived at the
[Music]
King's palace. When he
had to scream and they hit him many
times, they allowed him to enter through the
door and there was a second
door. He stayed at the second door
with the same kind of abuse for 100
years
and they let him pass through the second
door and there was a third
[Applause]
door. So in this way he passed through
six
doors, 600
years of
patience, and he arrived at the seventh
door
and passed through after 80,000 years, he spent 10,000
years at that
door and they let him pass through the seventh
door and there was the king behind the
seventh
[Music]
door and he said to him, "You are a very,
very cool guy."
You sat here for 80,000
years and people spat on you, beat you,
abused
you, and you didn't even
flinch. So I'm very
impressed, and I say, tell me whatever you want
and I'll give it to you.
[Music]
Because the king was amazed that
someone could keep that smile for
80,000
years. Who's telling the
story?
Then the
king's monk.
So he recited a poem to
[Music].
He doesn't want any
[Music]
food. I do
n't need any
delicious drinks. I don't need
fancy clothes. I don't need anything from
you. I'm satisfied with many
things. The reason I came here is
just to give you a
message.
[Applause]
[Music]
There's a person in your country who is
trying.
Wait, wait a minute, you're running out of
seeds. He's a great
saint. He's the most beautiful of all
beings. His name is Pure Light. He
has ended his own
suffering, and he's in your country, and he's
teaching
Dharma, and anyone who listens to him
will attain immortality. It's
only once every billion years that a
Buddha comes to your
world. It's like, incredibly
[Music]
Strange is the light, it is the lamp that brings
light to the whole world in the
[Music]
darkness. You have
been acting like a
little
[Music]
mado your things
like and it drove you
mad. How are you going to become a king
of the
dma?
He said all the things you can have
are
impermanent.
Your
life is
like the dew that forms on the grass
in the
morning.
If you are going to be mad, you will never learn
the
secret. If you become a
[Music]
bu puev all
beings, you will
become the being, the king of
all
living beings. If you want to be the servant
of all living beings,
you want to listen to this whole poem.
This poem is very long, I'm sorry, I'm
going to skip.
Leave arrogance and
bad thoughts behind. Go listen to this
bu de, work
hard, and learn to love all
beings. If you don't
[Music]
suffer
these words, leave your
pride and with great
respect. Knock,
loses, wait outside the
door. I apologize for anything I have
done in the
past. I have been
very busy with all my
worldly things, and now I am going  Listen to the
Buddha, I'm going to leave this bad
[Music]
attitude, I'm going to go with the
Buddha.
So he left the palace with his
friends, who
were only 80 by 10 million million million
friends. They
took many flowers and silk,
incense and
incense powder and threw it into the air and went to
see the
Buddha. So they went to where the
Buddha was, they made
prostrations, and in the presence of the
Buddha, the young King said these
words: You know, this crazy monk was 00
years away,
and because of his very
good attitude, I decided to accept him as my
teacher and decided to come with you and
make
[Music]
offerings.
This is
important, he is approaching the third
level because he
says, "Let me tell you all the mistakes I have
made in my
life. I want to do the four
powers. I want to stop all my bad, my
old bad
seeds,
and I want to learn to love all [
Music]
people. I want to become a Buddha
myself. I'm not going to act the way I
act." He
lowered his
[Music]
worldly work and focused on achieving
enlightenment and became a
monk. He
trained and reached the third level.
Mastery, if you are  Like this
king, and you listen to the
Dharma and make your heart
pure, you will reach the level called
mastery. The end of the
story,
but it's not the end of the
sutra, but that is the source of this
teaching. So you should
know it's two years old.
[Music] It's
actually Tibetans don't like
English or Spanish. I tried to read Don
Quixote, one page, and I
[Music]
gave up. Tibetan hasn't changed for 2000
years.
If you can read this, you can read the
sutra. You can read years of
reading, years, a million
years, more than a billion
years. To tell you how good that
other
Buddha was, I couldn't
[Music]
do it. So don't forget that Buddha
is telling this story to his
students
who are at the
gate.
[Music] It was
me before Buddha became a
Buddha. He was at the
gate, and they think the king
was...
So the third Buddha was outside
the gate of the fourth Buddha and helped him
become a
Buddha. So that's...
[Music]
History, now I'm going to start philosophy.
Sol est as. Now that
you're relaxed and not
worried about
philosophy, now we begin
philosophy. Last night I had a migraine. Okay,
let's see if we can get another one.
Here goes. I'm going
to tell you the
ancient definitions of the first four
paths. There are five
paths. All the people I know who
have a spiritual path carry these
five paths in their
evolution. It doesn't matter who you are, it does
n't matter your country or
religion. To become an angel,
you have to go through these
five quickly. Number
one: A big mess in your life. Number
two: Someone shows you the pen.
Number four: You perceive emptiness
directly. Right after that, you see
your future lives. You see Buddhas. You see the
whole path. The fourth
path: You get used to what
you saw and use it on your foolish husband.
Number four: You
have no more negative thoughts.
You reach
Nirvana. So here are the
traditional names for those
paths. I'm going to give you the notes afterward
for those of you who
care if your name
is
[Music].
First:
Tarpa,
Chpa,
Chpa. Traditional definition of the first
path: Tarpa means liberation,
freedom. Chpa means
to approach.
The ancient definition of the first
path is  Approaching liberation,
freedom, brought you closer to
freedom. A good
divorce, a
funeral,
cancer, well, like that, here,
liberate. The old definition of the second
[Music] Path:
approaching leaving it
[Music]
behind. Definition of the
preparation path. Old definition of the
Third
[Music] Path:
direct perception of
truth. It's
easy. Direct perception of the
[Music]
truth. Traditional definition of the fourth Path:
all that you realize after
[Music].
That's it. They are old, old
definitions. There is a famous book
called "
Approaching Leaving It Behind." It has four
steps.
The preparation path has
four
parts. This is a commentary by Ch Lama. We
know him. He wrote the commentary on the
diamond cutter [Music]. So we get close to
leaving it behind, the second
path. Why do we call the second
path approaching leaving it
[Music]
behind? Because we call it that. It will
say, "
Leaving it behind"
means the path of an [Music] person, the path
of someone who perceived emptiness
directly. The
definition of the second path is that you
are approaching reaching the third
path, which is the most
important one. So when we say leave it
all
behind  We're talking about perceiving emptiness
directly.
Leaving everything behind means perceiving emptiness
[Music]
directly. If you reach the path that's
close to leaving it
behind, you're close to perceiving
emptiness
[Music]
directly.
Yesterday I promised you a cappuccino.
I thought some of you would also want
orange. So there are 100 cappuccinos and
orange juices.
I hope there are
100.
So the second path is like the
introduction to the third
path and triggers the
third. So we call it close to
perceiving emptiness
directly. I'm
going to give you the names of the four
parts and you can have an orange juice or a
cappuccino. The first one in Sanskrit is
called [Music]. It means you're getting
[Music]
warm.
In English, when you're playing a game
and you have to find someone and they're getting
closer, you're saying 'hot, hot,
hot.' So the full name of
the first
part of the second
path—we're talking about the four
parts of the second
path—the understanding of the
pen—the first
part is called [
Music]. The full name is [
Music]. You're
getting warm, warm.
Why does it mean to get
warm,
like a bomb?
nuclear And if you start the second
path you're
[Music]
heating up And when you finish the four
parts and perceive it directly it's like
a
bomb it's like lighting the fuse
of the
bomb
if someone asks you in the
debate park what is the name of the first of
the four parts of the second
path you can
say You can say it's
heating up
m r d h a n a
me
of m means the Summit of a
mountain
there's a big
debate also debate why they call it the
Summit the peaks And you still have to
get to the
fourth you have to understand something when
you reach the second these
first two it's possible you fall that you
come back
in Tibetan it's called
y What does it
mean they
tremble but the second one is higher than
the
first So we call it the
summit of the two that tremble that
are not well grounded It's the
best one
means the Summit means the one that
trembles
[Music]
least want to hear a
joke there's a famous comment for
laa written by a
Lama problem with that program had
a lot more
problem they gave him the charge of sculpting
elur he made some
mistakes they
executed him We are
more
but he wrote  A great comment from La
Vid, a weapon before he
died. So here goes this
joke
between the two steps, not well
established. He's making a
joke, then he
explained.
[Music]
Third,
today in yoga class I
said that comes from... it's a
very
long story, but the complete ancient Sanskrit is... it
means
patience. It's the name of the third
perfection. Don't get mad,
but sometimes it means you're so
patient that you become a
master, like a master, a mastery. You
become a
master. All the words that start
with k and s in Sanskrit came into
English with q and...
[Music]
u, quiet.
How the word quiet became...
and it became calm.
It became
calm. It literally means calm, calm.
[Music]
p is the one we're talking about. It's the one we
want to
reach. I'm
going to give you the last one and we're going to get
our
[Music]
drinks. I'm going to get something quick. Let me
see that I pronounce it right, I
spell it
right.
[Music] It
means the highest, the
best. That's why the person who built it did it
in the village of
Agra. It means the
highest and...  Dharma
means the fourth. The fourth level of the
second path is called Ag
Dharma and it means the highest in the
world.
And sometimes it's called
Lay, meaning the highest of the
world. So the full name for the
fourth
part, and you see why I told you this
story,
first,
highest world
means that before you go to the
highest world,
before you perceive emptiness
directly, the highest
Supreme reality, the best thing that can
happen to you
is the highest in the universe. It
's not the highest in the
normal universe. If you go beyond that, you are already
in another
reality. What is that Supreme reality called?
If you go higher than the fourth part of the
second path, then you see the
Supreme reality in that fourth
part. You can see that karma
opens in your
mind. You
can see how the image comes out
and how the
parts go. The
cocoon is always making
cocoons in the fourth
part, which is not during meditation.
You can be standing boiling water for
tea
and suddenly you see the image of the
pot come out of your
mind and reach the
stove.  They can see
directly. That's the highest thing that
can happen to them before they perceive
emptiness
directly.
So if they see a seed open
in their mind and create the pot or their husband
or
anything within a few hours, they will perceive
emptiness
directly. If they perceive emptiness
directly at that moment, their body...
They begin to
change and start to become an
angel, and nothing can
stop that. If it's well-founded, nothing
can
stop it. So the best thing that can
happen to them in this
world is to see how the
seed opens and see something
[Music]
come out. A few hours later,
they will enter
meditation, and with their eyes closed, they will
see the
Supreme Reality. And if that
happens, their body begins to
change at that
instant, and nothing can
stop it. And
then
we're going to have cappuccinos. I'll make a
few
more on the left side and the cappuccinos on the
right.
[Applause]
Cheers! I like the explanation of
these four steps in
Elida. They also explain them in the Middle Way school,
but that will give you a
headache. So I'm going to give it to you on
Saturday so you can go home with a
headache. Today, just for a few minutes, I'm going
to talk about Dearma,
which you've heard me talk about a lot. It's
called... I do the translation DEA as in "
house of
treasure." Abida means "
high knowledge." This is a famous book that was
written 1700
years ago by the master
[Music]
Vandu
is a great book because inside that
book
[Music]
it says Let me seito
directly
[Applause]
that's it
I memorized it when I had
[Music]
something
patience or here it means
[Music]
mastery that
F
in
code is all like a
secret you manage to reach the third
level not go to a lower Renaissance
it
says it.
Now there's another famous book
dearma written by the master
deas half-
brother
called of all Chinese Buddhism
aanga is the most
important one.
The brother wrote a book of
abida it's
called in Tibetan se
[Music]
a collection
deid means
collection.
And that's a
high school and I like its explanation of what's
happening on the four
levels. So we're going to go with the
next class and we want to pass
vi don't
go down
somebody Cancel those
flights how it
works we're going to do it on
Saturday but
today I thought you'd like to know the
explanation of
[Music]
asanga is commenting
on asanga about
who is the disciple of
js is like the one who sits next to
js se became the
Throne Holder after
[Music]
Tonapa, his name means the holder
of the
[Music]
throne.
Here is his explanation of what
happens on the four
levels, and you will understand because it
is connected to the
[Music]
feather.
What happens on the first
level, the first of the four
steps,
and you begin to have an understanding
about the four truths of the
area. What are the four truths of the
area? Number
one: pain,
suffering. Number
two: it has a
cause. Number
three: you can
stop it. Number
four: there is a method, there is a
path. These are called the four
truths of the
[Music]
area. What happens on the first
level of the four levels of the path
of
[Music]
preparation? You begin to have a
clear, intellectual, not direct understanding. It
means that your mind becomes
very clear with
it.
[Music]
Tantrics studied tantra for years
at Diamond
Mountain. It is another use of the word. It
means I am
amit. It is
like
divine pride. Like those
bullfighters,
I am
amitu. That is
called confidence in tantra. I
am, and the other half
is, I see myself as
amit.  Their
minds have to imagine that they have
hair
and they are very
intelligent. That's called
Clarity in
Tantra. There are two
important parts to the first
level. I
am Spider-
Man and I see myself as
Spider-Man. Here, that
Clarity... what happens in the first part
of the second
path? Total mental clarity,
intellectually,
about the four
truths. This life is
pain. There is a
reason for it. You can stop it,
and there is
one. You have
Clarity. What happens right before you
have Clarity about the four
truths? You had your
personal disaster. You were lucky enough to
have a
personal tragedy. You look so beautiful and
elegant. I know you don't
belong
here, but some tragedy brought you
here. You should be in a great
restaurant. You should be in
Acapulco, but you are
here, and I can see that you are beautiful and
strong,
and something brought you here instead of
Acapulco. And usually, it's a
tragedy. The
second part: your mind becomes
Clear.
Mental Clarity. So that part is the same.
Mental Clarity, direct or intellectual perception,
just
intellectual, about emptiness. About
emptiness
with a z instead of
[Music]
Simba. Now you have to understand
something: all things in the
universe are or
zba  It means objects of the mind.
Zimba means the
mind. You can divide everything into objects you
see and the one who sees, the
observer.
When I see this
rosary, the
rosary, the one who sees, the
observer. You can divide all
things in the
universe between things you see, taste,
or think about,
objects and
subjects. There are two types of
subjects: one is the
mind, and the other is
Nick, the person who has the mind, whom
we call the
subject. Nick is enjoying the
cappuccino. The cappuccino is the
object, and Nick is the
subject. When you reach the second
[Music]
level,
you begin to
understand the emptiness of
[Music]
objects. The pen is an object. A
subject is an object.
No object, subject. Does it think? If it does
n't think, it's an
object. The cappuccino is a subject.
No, it can't
think. If you want to debate something in the
debate park,
try to
see if I can read
Anton's mind right now. Is it a subject or
an
object? I'm not going to
tell you, but generally, at the second
level, you begin to understand the
pen. You begin to understand the
[Music]
pen,
and your mind becomes
clear. It doesn't happen in meditation, but
you have to be
meditating all the time.  Days you have to
be
meditating, waterfall of water from the
ceiling, but generally you have to be
meditating every day, otherwise you can't get
here. They think it happens on the third
level.
It talks about the
feather, about its
essence, about
objects, totally clear, about the
emptiness of the
feather, something that is
out there completely
clear. Your teacher taught it to you like 500
times.
Don't teach us that over and over again. No, no, no, I'm not
going to
stop. If I don't do something good in my life, I'm going
to keep you out of the
lower realms. Halfway through the
third level, you begin to understand the emptiness
of the
subjects of the
mind.
You begin to have
clarity. That's not very difficult. I
can teach it to you in a minute.
[Music]
Ready?
Then you finish the third level and you're
safe. You'll have a
guarantee. So all of
us, all
day long, all day long, our minds are
blah blah.
I know my mind is talking all
day, and I can experience that
directly. And then I ask my
friends, "Berta, is your mind talking like that all day?" Yes, yes. Me too.
[Music] Me
too. I used to interview all the
students who were assigned to my class
in New
York, I already told you this
story. I was working
full time, so I would take you out to
eat, and I took a
friend once. So, do you want to come to my class? And he
said, "What do you do?"
[Music] "
On
[Music]
drugs." He looked me in the eyes and said, "I steal
things.
I have to inject heroin every
day." And I was actually very
nervous. He said,
and I asked him, "So how much does it cost you
each
day?" Like, $ a day. He said,
and I said, "Well, you know." I was
trying to have a
conversation. I've never met
a heroin addict before, so what you do gives me an idea. Since I
was
little, my mind is talking all the
time inside my head. Well, it's
also very strong, very loud all the
time. And I realized that when I inject
heroin, it calms down for a couple of
hours. It's worth it
for 50 an hour. It's call, and I'm
[Music]
happy. We're talking about
this.
So, you are the people who
are listening to the blah blah blah. You
are the blah blah.
Blades bl bles bl
bles,
which
can't be the
two of you. Can't be how are you?
[Music]
Berta, you're the ones listening to
the bl
bl, it makes the bl
[Music]
bl
and you're just
listening, I'm going to tell you another
story. I used to be the translator for
my
teacher when he spoke Tibetan. My
enemy translated, I didn't
translate. He came to our
temple, the board called me.
Michael Lama comes to the
temple, and I was like, can I do it? Can I do it?
And they said, "We need your
help." And I said, "Yes, I know, I can do it,
I can do it."
So you agree to make
500 momos?
Momo is like a Tibetan hamburger. I
said, "We need you to make 500
momos. You don't need a
[Music]
translator."
My other student of my Lama, I
'm jealous of him. I'm
talking about him.
Someone is talking in your mind, I remember.
But sometimes I had to translate for
my
Lama. So I went up to his room, and if
someone came to his room, I would talk to them.
I translated from
English to
English. It was my
job. One person came to talk to
him, and I said, "Can I
help you?" He
usually has a table and a
comfortable chair, and the  The table is covered with
Tibetan books and he's
reading and reading and the
person comes in, does
prostrations and he keeps
reading and
[Applause]
says they were
already telling him I have a problem and he was saying
Ah What's your
problem? I feel
depressed maybe I'll commit
suicide Don't do
that, don't get so depressed You're still
here You can Now you can
go
Take them I have to tell them I'm sorry Do you
want some tea?
After the person was going to go
upstairs and I lived together for 25
years Just the
two of us We're like an old
married couple He went upstairs and opened the
door
This guy is going to commit
suicide He asked you for
help You told him Don't do it
What kind of compassion is that? And he
said that's the only thing you can
tell them It's a seed opening in their
mind The seed is going to say
depressing things No one can
stop it Don't do that You're
not in
control You can't push those trees back into
the
ground Look at those trees They're
big I don't like that tree I'm going to push it back into
the
ground I don't like it When my mind is
depressed It's too
late
You can attend to the thoughts of  The
following week, but not the ones from
now, they come from the week of
[Music].
Before, you can teach the
depressed person to have good thoughts. The
following
week, those thoughts in the
present moment are not
possible because we are talking about
this. That is the emptiness of the
subjects. They
have it from the
mind. The mind also comes from
seeds. Feathers come from seeds,
and the observer comes from
seeds. That's all
easy. Now you have finished level
3. If you think about this for the rest
of your
lives, it is impossible to fall to a
lower realm. That's
all.
How can I remember to think about
this? Your life will
remind you. Your husband will divorce
you. Your child will get
sick. Someone will key your car the
day after you
bought it, and you will say, "Why, A,
and Lu, you will remember to think about
this." He will
remember. He will say, "Samsara has only one
good thing. It reminds you that you have to get out
of
it. Samsara is like a sticky note, a little piece of paper
that you
stick on. You don't forget that you have to get out
of
samsara." Do the fourth and
[Music].
We finished the third. You begin to
understand the  Emptiness of the
subjects. So you know what's going to
happen in the
room. You fully understand the
subjects, the emptiness of the
subjects,
and immediately after that, you perceive
the emptiness
directly within an hour or two,
and your body starts to change into an
angel's body at that
moment, and nothing can stop it.
Okay. If you get angry, you can stop it.
Okay,
good news. And then
we stop at the second
level when you start to understand the
pen. You can still
get angry, but it's not going to destroy your
bank account. After level two,
your buma is
safe; you can't
destroy it anymore. Very
good, lauma.
Good, so
interested
?